Their fun summer break has come to an end.
YEAR 2 CLASS 7
CULTURE FESTIVAL PLANS
Time to begin planning
for the culture festival!
So...
We wanted to do a play, but we
didn't get it in the lottery.
WHAAAAAAAAT?
Instead, year 2 class 7 has been assigned
to the food and beverage division.
OOOOOOOH!
Then, after school...
THE ELITES CALLED
INTO ACTION
(THE GOING-
HOME CLUB)
the elites are called into action!
Oh, were you and Tani at the
library over summer break?
Huh? How'd you know that?
Gapacho saw you.
Gapacho again?
What's this? A library date?
That's so pure.
Well, in the end, it was actually...
Hang on. Never mind me!
Yamada, how did things turn out for you?
Huh?
Before summer break, you exchanged
contact info. What happened?
Oh! I want to know, too!
Well... we did text a little.
But that's pretty much it.
What's this?
It's completely hopeless.
What?
We did text back and forth,
but I'm just not used to it at all.
I think way too much about how to reply.
There!
BUZZ
He replied already?!
I'VE NEVER HAD A PART-TIME JOB BEFORE,
BUT ONCE I GO TO UNIVERSITY,
I THINK I MIGHT LIKE TO TRY
WORKING PART-TIME AT A BOOKSHOP.
READ
REALLY?
But Yamada-kun's replies are so short.
Huh? Am I writing much long messages
for no reason?
I get so scared that
I might be horribly creepy.
If you don't like it,
you could ignore him.
YOU CAN'T
HELP IT, THOUGH
No! I...
I don't think I don't like it.
But when he asked if he could call me...
WANT TO TALK
ON A CALL?
SORRY. I'M OUT
RIGHT NOW
I've already turned him down twice.
READ
OKAY!
Oh, dear.
In the moment, I lied,
and I think he knows.
I don't want to push him away, but I've
become someone who seems like I do.
RESISTANCE
TO MALES: 0
Sounds kinda borderline.
But if she texts back, then maybe she's
just not comfortable talking or something.
That seems totally possible.
I just don't know anymore.
But I want to know
what kind of person she is.
Yamada, I've had this image of you dating
laughing, cheerful girls up to now.
Really? Sounds like fun.
Yeah, that's true, but...
Let's try a little review!
Yamada, you're seriously hilarious!
The man who's easily attracted
to an unlikely smile, Yamada!
One day...
You've probably already realized this,
but... Yamada, I'm in love with you.
OF COURSE
HE HAD
NO IDEA
What?!
CURIOUS
ABOUT
(LIKES...?)
FEW
CHANCES
TO
INTERACT
LIKES
JUST
FINE
GET
ALONG
WELL
TOGETHER
How about we date, then?
Yeah!
HAS
EXPERIENCE
DATING
ONE-SIDED
LOVE RETURN
RATE: 0%
BUT IN THEIR OWN WAY, THOSE ARE GOOD MEMORIES...
You know, despite Yamada being like this,
he stayed with his last girlfriend
for a pretty long time.
What do you mean, "like this"?
I mean, now we're just good friends.
Sounds amazing.
That's the youth I wish I'd had.
Azu, you still have time for that youth.
But I totally get it!
I'm so jealous of people
who have really dated.
They'll always have that
experience to draw on.
Suzuki, you're dating now, aren't you?
This is basically my first time,
so I'm feeling my way along.
What?
Hey, don't pretend like you and
Ricchan were never a thing.
Ricchan?
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
If we just pick out stuff that's
green and leafy, we should be fine.
OUT SHOPPING BECAUSE THEY
LOST AT ROCK-PAPER-SCISSORS
Uniforms from our school.
We want button badge covers
and plushie stands, right?
Plushie?
Hey, Hon-chan, over there...
It's Tani-kun, the guy
I mentioned before.
What?
Oh, the bespectacled light novel
protagonist with a gyaru girlfriend.
What does that mean?
Hey, Tani.
We're checking out and
getting out of here.
TRAUMA RESPONSE TO GIRLS WHISPERING
They were clearly looking
at us and saying something.
What was it?
GIRLS WHO COULDN'T CARE LESS
Hundred yen shops
seriously have everything.
What's that about? Who's Ricchan?
U-Um, well...
Hey, that's messed up.
You're saying he doesn't count, right?
No, it's not like that, you know?
I feel so bad about what I did.
I was just so inexperienced.
Hey! Look!
SURPRISE!!
We finished the giant menu boards!
BOOM
Wow! Those are amazing!
They're just like
the ones from that shop!
Right?
Oh, Sato, did you do the lettering?
The pictures, too.
Whoa! You're basically a pro!
Hey, Yamada. What kind of
person is this Ricchan?
She totally is, right?
If we had a little more...
Huh?
She's a total genius.
A super great guy!
NONSPECIFIC!!
Yeah?
Right? Right? Right?
Oh, he said he'll be
at the culture festival,
so you can meet him.
What?
So, what should we do next?
Let's go eat that thing
we saw last time.
Good idea! Let's go!
Hey, Tani.
Is Suzuki your first girlfriend?
Yeah.
In that case...
Do you ever think stuff like,
you're not sure how dating works?
Or you don't have enough experience?
Do you have doubts like that?
I mean, he doesn't seem like the
type to worry about that stuff.
I used to look down on Tani,
but now I'm trying to use him
as a reference. That's so pathetic.
I think those things.
What?
I'm constantly doubting myself.
Really?
MEAT
It's done!
CULTURE FESTIVAL, DAY 1
(STUDENTS AND STAFF ONLY)
CULTURE FESTIVAL
Start the culture festival!
All right! Let's enjoy day one!
Yeah!
YOU WIN
SOLD OUT! THANK YOU!
CULTURE FESTIVAL, DAY 2
(VISITORS ALLOWED)
On day two, the festival
is open to the public!
DOKKIRI BINKEY
Today, Tani-kun and I will be
walking around together!
You're so annoying.
Bye. Have fun.
Bye!
Suzuki, your shirt is already all black.
Tani-kun, you should write something, too!
Like what?
A message to me!
"To Suzuki-san..."
Stop it. Don't read it aloud.
Don't read it silently either.
Hey. You're still calling her
"Suzuki-san"?
Just "Suzuki" would be better, right?
True.
Don't just agree!
BUT
NORMALLY
THAT'S...
COZY CAFE
Where should we start?
JAPANESE-STYLE
FOOD STALL
Tani-kun, how did you
look around last year?
The class project was a play,
so I didn't look around much that day.
What? Then I'll put the perfect plan
together and show you around!
Thank you.
First, we'll prioritize the things
that have set times.
REST AREA
When we get tired, we'll get tea and
baked sweets at the PTA's place.
GLOBAL WARMING
And we can't forget class
and club exhibitions!
PHOTOGRAPHY
CLUB
EXHIBITION
I have nothing to do.
WELCOME TO
OUR EXHIBITION!!
TAKE YOUR TIME
LOOKING AROUND
People keep peeking in and then leaving.
Could it be that I'm giving off
a negative aura?
Huh? There's an exhibition here, too?
Oh.
These two are...
It's actually more awkward when
I know the person a little.
What?
No, no, no.
She must be saying, "You two work
in the library together, right?"
I'm sorry! We're not close enough for
that to work as a conversation hook!
Excuse me. Is it all right for us
to talk while we look around?
Oh... That's completely fine.
Wow.
I wonder if they really are dating.
When does the photography club
do their activities?
You're going to talk to me?!
Oh, um, we don't get together as a group.
It's more like we all work individually.
Wow, really?
Oh, I like this photo!
The colors are beautiful!
That was me.
Really? That's amazing!
No, it's nothing much.
Oh, but I really like this one!
Did you use special techniques or cameras?
No, nothing special.
It's a camera meant for beginners.
Really?
Wow!
That's amazing!
Tani-kun, which one do you like?
This one.
A cat?
I mean, it's a good photo.
But, Tani-kun, that's just because
you like cats, right? Honestly!
Right?
Thanks for teaching us so much!
Somehow...
I feel like I spoke pretty well!
I kept our conversational rally going,
and there weren't any long silences!
SELF-CONFIDENCE (A TINY BIT) UP
If only I could do that every time.
Being clear without getting too nervous...
Where are you right now? I'll head to you.
More cheerful and pleasant...
What can you see right now?
Energetic and...
Huh?
Oh! I, um...
I haven't seen you in a while.
Huh? Hello? Hey!
Hey, Taira! Why don't you
go out front for a while?
It's fine. And I don't know
who might show up today either.
You made all that effort to change.
You're gonna regret this.
No one asked you.
Hey!
Go on! The world outside is
more fun than you might expect.
Stop it!
Oh, hey!
Is Yamada in your class?
Oh. Yes.
Huh? He was here just a little while ago.
What? Really?
After hanging up like that,
I wonder where he went.
I guess it doesn't matter. Thanks!
I'll look for him myself!
He's so handsome.
HE READS AS
"POPULAR WITH
THE LADIES"...
Wait. Was that...
Oh, that was so much fun!
Isn't it great that they gave us
prizes at Struck Out?
It's dangerous if you don't look
where you're going.
Yes, sir!
Huh?
Suzuki-san.
Miyu?
I knew it was you, Miyu!
It's been a while.
Rihito.
Huh? Oka?
Satou! It's been a while!
You came.
Yeah.
Someone you know?
Yeah, from middle school.
Um, Tani-kun...
This is my classmate from
middle school, Oka-kun.
Oka, did you come alone?
Nah. I'm here with friends
from high school.
I'm just operating solo
for a little while.
I heard that Yamada, Sato,
and Miyu were all in the same class,
so I thought I might be able to see you!
Yeah, it's really been a while!
How long has it been?
Probably since we graduated, right?
Have you been well?
I'm doing all right.
This is so awkward.
It's been so long that all I can do is
smile and talk about safe topics.
Hey, Yamada! Please get here soon!
I mean, it's been so long,
I thought it'd be fine if
I acted like nothing happened,
but it's not working at all!
Like I said, nothing's better
than rhythm stuff!
If only things hadn't gotten
weird back then.
And that's why your thing
is so weird, Miyu!
MIDDLE SCHOOL
YEAR 3
No human can ever escape the beat!
What authority said that?
Hey, hey!
Are the two of you dating?
You're always together.
That's right!
Ugh, what a pain.
Huh? No, we're not.
Shouldn't you just date already?
Right? They look good together.
Go on, Rihito! Right? Right?
This is one of those things where the
more we deny it, the weirder it'll get.
If I go with the flow, and Miyu
completely shuts it down, then...
Miyu, do you want to go out with me?
Huh?
What?!
Well, um, I don't know.
Wow! Congrats!
Huh?
CAN'T SAY
IT WAS A JOKE IN
THIS ATMOSPHERE...
Wait, wait! You can't seriously...
I guess it doesn't matter.
Both of us started out with an
"I'm not vehemently opposed" mindset.
This is awkward.
What did we used to talk about?
It used to be that all we'd do was laugh.
Now that we're dating,
it isn't fun at all.
So...
Do you want to try doing something
that's more couple-ish?
I'm not feeling "I don't hate him"
so much as I am "actually, I like him."
Oh. This isn't right.
I can't explain it well,
but there's no mistake.
Somehow, this isn't right.
Yeah. I thought so.
This isn't us, right?
That's not our groove together.
This never happened.
Let's go back to how we were!
Friends, right?
I made him say that.
I forced him have to be considerate of me.
I'm sorry.
Why?
WENT
WITH
THE
FLOW
Why is it that the more you feel you're
at fault for something in your memories...
...the more you keep getting stuck
on the feelings you don't like?
NONCOMMITTAL
HALF-
HEARTED
MOVES
So, um...
If I apologized... That would be
too self-centered of me.
I just want to make myself feel better.
Hey, Miyu?
When our middle school
group gets together,
you make sure not to
come if I'm there, right?
What?
That's gotta be a pain, right?
Don't worry about it. Any of it.
Okay?
Let's hang out like normal
again sometime. We're friends!
Here. We're good now.
Yay!
Y-Yay.
See you later. I'm gonna look for Dayama.
Rihito!
I made it so you had to be
considerate of me again!
What? You guys hadn't
worked things out yet?
It's sort of... I think
we finally just did.
It's like all the uneasiness I felt
in the past disappeared all at once.
Hey. Maybe you guys from the same
middle school are cool with this,
but the feeling of alienation
over here is intense.
Sorry.
Right, Tani-kun?
Friends?
Well, I'll leave the rest
to you two youngsters.
Wait!
Which is why there was a second
where we thought "let's try dating,"
but we ended up thinking
"no, this is wrong" pretty quickly.
Trying to cover it up
would have felt more wrong,
so I told him everything, but...
did I dig my own grave?
We made a weird mistake, but he was
my friend then and he's my friend now.
I see.
You understand what happened?
Yes.
I wonder if Tani-kun
doesn't like women with pasts.
Tani-kun, I think of you
as my first boyfriend!
Sorry you had to make me feel better.
I think the problem here lies with me.
I'll go sort out my thoughts.
What?!
Ricchan!
Where have you been?
Sorry. Sorry.
But thanks to you, I think Miyu
and I may have made up.
Huh? You two weren't getting along?
No, you know what I mean, right?
I mean, I do know, but still.
DOES
NOT
KNOW
Well, we're just gonna erase
a bunch of stuff, you know?
Huh?
I remember my mistakes perfectly well.
Actually, instead of romance-type stuff,
I think my desire not to be hated
by my friends is far stronger.
What?
There's no one who'd hate you, Ricchan!
THIS IS WHY I LOVE
MY MIDDLE SCHOOL FAM...
Yama!
But what did he mean?
"The problem lies with me"?
It's probably just jealousy.
RIBBIT
But there's really nothing
between me and Rihito.
Well, Ricchan is a hottie.
Even if he is handsome and we're
good friends and he's a boy...
for me, that doesn't add up to romance.
That's what I learned back then!
There isn't nothing.
There's self-reflection and regret.
Still... first boyfriend
and first girlfriend.
It's so sweet and pure.
My own history is already far too sullied.
No, that has nothing to do with anything.
An innocent past, your firsts...
The fact that having nothing in your past
is considered "pure" is weird, isn't it?
What's going on?
It's like a switch flipped.
Even if I were a woman who'd slept
with a hundred people in my past!
Slept with?
If I want to face the person in front of
me with sincerity now and in the future,
then that's pure, isn't it?
All right!
I AM
YOUR
"NOW"!
I'm gonna go to Tani-kun!
Okay.
Let's go!
Wow.
For some reason...
I want to be in love.
I'm so sorry!
DROOP
Oh. It's just you, Taira.
Hey!
LET'S HAVE
THE BEST,
FUNNEST DAY!
-S
I knew from the start that she'd
have friends I didn't know about.
There's no point in feeling unsettled
by things that are already past.
It's just...
Let's hang out like normal again sometime.
THEN WHY
DOES HE
STILL CALL
HER BY HER
FIRST NAME?
IF THERE'S A
GET-TOGETHER,
WILL SHE SEE
HIM THERE?
STRESS
little things about the present
and the future worry me.
Why is it that with each passing day,
instead of growing bolder,
I grow greedier?
Why is my heart getting smaller?
Tani-kun!
I love you.
Tani-kun, I...
Tani-kun, the way that you don't lie and
say exactly what you mean... I love that.
But sometimes...
you'll say, "I'm totally fine,"
but actually your thoughts
are spinning around, right?
It's fine.
Even if you can't be totally clear,
or if you're still thinking...
If you feel anxious and unsettled
for some reason, just tell me that.
Well, we're about to start
the awards ceremony,
so if all students could assemble
in the gym please.
Should we just stay here like this?
There's no point in comparing myself
to others, but I got anxious anyway.
And I hated that I felt that way.
That's what you hated? Not me?
Yeah.
I'm sorry for making you feel like that.
It's fine.
Is there anything else?
Suzuki-san, you seem like
you'd like someone like him.
What?!
SUDAKEN
You say that, Tani-kun,
but aren't there a lot of people who
would suit you better than me?
DEMURE
TYPES ?
No, there aren't.
Yes, there are!
Who?
I don't know, but...
What are we talking about here?
Miyu.
Is that what everyone called you?
Huh? Um, no, not really.
With Rihito, it was more like
he was being contrarian.
Rihito.
Tani-kun.
If there's something you'd like
to say, then please say it.
No, it's fine.
Year 2 Class 7...
In that case, Yuusu—
Tani Yuusuke, Suzuki Miyu,
please report to the gym!
Oh, they noticed.
Well, let's go! Yuusuke-kun!
Everyone's already gone!
We're definitely gonna get teased
about getting summoned together.
Right, Yuusuke-san?
TO SUZUKI-SAN,
I LOOK FORWARD TO
OUR CONTINUED RELATIONSHIP
-TANI
TELL ME ALL KINDS
OF STORIES AGAIN SOMETIME
-REINA
ME TOO
-NA
ME TOO!
-YAMA
DOESN'T
KNOW
ANYTHING
YOUR VOICE
IS TOO LOUD
YOU TALK
TOO MUCH
You don't have to
force yourself to call me that.